Amanda L. Burr

UX/UI DESIGNER

UX/UI designer with a background in digital communication campaigns and project management. Over 10 years in Marketing and corporate communications. Experienced in working with a variety of stakeholders to customize projects that meet goals and deliver consistent user experiences.

Professional experience

Securian Financial Group - St. Paul, MN Website Manager & Editor, 2017-Present

- Positions the company's internal site as a central hub for employee communications by implementing new features and functionality to increase engagement.
- Maintains and creates content on company website by implementing user experience best practices and applying digital style guide standards.
- Collaborates with internal stakeholders to communicate complex topics to a wide audience and create a communication plan.

Corp Communications Project Manager, 2015-2017

- Partnered with stakeholders to support communication needs for internal marketing campaigns.
- Supported team by providing printing, proofreading, copywriting and project management services.
- Made recommendations and copy edits to the company's internal website while partnering with project stakeholders.

Contact info



651-428-9450



amandalburr@gmail.com



St. Paul, Minnesota

Вē

https://www.behance.net/amandaburr1

Education

UI Design Certification, CareerFoundry Oct 2020 - July 2021, Certificate

University of Minnesota - Twin CitiesBachelor of Arts - Journalism

Skills

Prototyping
Wireframing
Employer Branding
User Personas
Mood Boards
Style Guides
User Flows

Tools

InVision Adobe XD, Illustrator, InDesign, Photoshop HTML5 JavaScript CSS3

UX/UI projects

CareerFoundry: Intensive project-based training program with a focus on conducting user research, rapid prototyping, creating cohesive brand guidelines, wirefraiming and designing for iOS and Android.

Tools used: In Vision, Adobe XD, Photoshop and Illustrator.

Shop Small

An app that helps users locate small businesses in their community.

Conducted user interviews, created user personas, utilized rapid prototyping techniques, and designed low-fi, mid-fi and final wireframes.

View the project here: https:// www.behance.net/gallery/ 119063803/Shop-Small-Discoversmall-businesses

Pinchpenny

A simple-to-use app that helps users budget and reach their financial goals.

Created user testing methods, designed mood boards and style guides, developed user personas, wireframes and final mockups.

View the project here: https://www.behance.net/gallery/119064793/Pinchpenny-a-money-saving-tool

NextRead

A book recommendation app that also connects users to their friends.

Researched iOS and Android design guidelines, conducted a competitor analysis, developed interactive prototypes for user testina.

View the project here: https://www.behance.net/gallery/119065255/NextRead-a-book-recommendation-app